<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="https://tungeric.github.io//feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://tungeric.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://tungeric.github.io//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-10-23T13:42:50-07:00</updated><id>https://tungeric.github.io//</id><title type="html">Eric Tung</title><subtitle>I spent my life building concrete foundations - literally. Now I'm aiming for the clouds - also kind of literally but mostly I just wanted to be punny there.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">SpotMe</title><link href="https://tungeric.github.io//spotme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SpotMe" /><published>2017-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://tungeric.github.io//spotme</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tungeric.github.io//spotme/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/spotme-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aldahir15.github.io/SpotMeApp/&quot;&gt;Live demo page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture you just discovered this hot new restaurant in a popular part of town. You make a reservation and you drive up the night up eager for a night of great food and drink. Upon getting to your destination, however, you realize that there. Is. No. Parking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You turn off the main street onto a residential side street and you experience the all-too-familiar torment where every time you think you see an open spot you realize that it’s only open because it’s in front of a driveway. And you think “there has to be a better way!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well now there is! (Sort of.) Enter SpotMe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SpotMe is a mobile application I’m working on in a team of 4 engineers starting in mid-October of 2017. We’ve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;feature-demo&quot;&gt;Feature Demo&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;facebook-login&quot;&gt;Facebook login&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first challenges I tackled for this project was O-Auth. O-Auth was much more complex than anything I had learned at App Academy thus far, and took much longer than I expected. Here’s what the flow for the authentication ended up being for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I used a website called &lt;a href=&quot;www.auth0.com&quot;&gt;Auth0&lt;/a&gt; to help me with the process. Altogether, Auth0 didn’t actually save me any steps, but because it was built to handle multiple logins through multiple sites all using a single endpoint from the developer perspective (meaning the process to add Google authentication would be theoretically minimal), it seemed to be the right way to go. The built-in debugger was very helpful in me figuring out where I was going wrong in my requests.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using Auth0, I pinged Facebook for an access code. This is a short-ish code that you’ll need for Step 3.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Facebook (and other websites - including Auth0!) have a Client ID along with a Client Secret that you have to keep, well, &lt;em&gt;secret&lt;/em&gt;. I ended up storing this in the backend using the Figaro gem, in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;application.yml&lt;/code&gt; file, so the next step is to ping our backend with the access code we got in Step 2, so Rails can ping Facebook for the actual authorization token.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rails pings Facebook for the actual authorization token.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So Facebook sends you the authorization token back. We’re done, right? NOPE. It gives you the token back in a Base64Url encoded format, which I then used the jwtDecoder library to decode. When the token is decoded, we finally have access to our Facebook information (email, profile, etc) and we can sign in to our app normally.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is glorious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/spotme-fb-login.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-maps-and-seeing-all-your-spots&quot;&gt;Google Maps and seeing all your spots&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming soon…&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="mobile" /><category term="react-native" /><category term="redux" /><category term="graphql" /><category term="apollo" /><category term="rails" /><category term="ruby" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SoundCrown</title><link href="https://tungeric.github.io//soundcrown/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SoundCrown" /><published>2017-09-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-09-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://tungeric.github.io//soundcrown</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tungeric.github.io//soundcrown/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/soundcrown-logo-wide.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;soundcrown&quot;&gt;SOUNDCROWN&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcrown.herokuapp.com&quot;&gt;Live page on Heroku&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a project between Week 8 and Week 10 of App Academy and is meant to be a clone of the popular web-streaming service SoundCloud. This application is built using Ruby on Rails for backend with PostgreSQL for the database and ReactJS for the front end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-features&quot;&gt;Key Features:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User Authentication and secure sign-in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User uploaded pictures and audio files&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continuous playback of music while navigating the site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Users can leave comments on tracks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ss1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;ss4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The splash page is designed to look somewhat like SoundCloud’s home page - I used essentially the same words as SoundCloud has with the exception of a few references to royalty and kingdoms (my site is named “SoundCROWN” after all).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users can log in or create an account using the buttons in the top right or in the center of the page - or they can scroll all the way to the bottom of the page and eventually there will be buttons there too! Alternatively, click the “Demo” button for a quick tour around the page with full user capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passwords are protected using BCrypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ss2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;ss4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once logged in, the site will direct you to our Stream page, which features the newest and most-played tracks on the application. If you click the play button on any of these tracks, a music bar will appear at the bottom of the screen and begin playing music. You can now navigate anywhere in the site and the music will continue to play until you tell it to stop or until the page is refreshed manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ss3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;ss4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users also have their own page where they can freely edit their avatar and tracks. Note that the url for users is simply &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(root directory)/:username&lt;/code&gt;. I chose this so users can have an easier time just typing in other usernames as opposed to trying to remember the user_id. This did pose some challenges as Rails is predisposed to link associations with ids, so during any data transfer both the username as well as the id must be passed through. The music essentially plays the existing playlist unless you click out of it so if you started playing a track on the Stream page, it will continue to go down the list of tracks in the stream page (or the order can be randomized if you wish - just click the shuffle button in the play bar!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ss4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;ss4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the play bar you have more options than just shuffle. If you want to play one specific track on repeat, click the repeat button. Next and previous buttons as well as play/pause buttons are also available. You can also adjust your position on the track using the track progress slider in the middle of the bar. Lastly, the track can be muted in a pinch by clicking the volume control button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big challenge for me was to have the page communicate with the play bar on whether the track is playing or not - this is why the play button turns to the pause button when you click it. To accomplish this, I had to send the play data from the play bar up to the root application level and back down into the track item. This street goes two ways, though, so the same data has to be transferred back to the music player in the event that the user clicks “play” in the page instead of on the play bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ss6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;ss4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Files can be uploaded at any time by clicking the “Upload” button in the nav bar. This will enable users to choose an audio file and a cover art for their track. The only required info for the upload to work are the track and the title. To be honest, the description isn’t even shown anywhere on the page, but use it to hide secret messages and easter eggs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ss5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;ss4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tracks also have their own pages where users can play the track as well as leave comments. Comments are displayed in reverse chronological order for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;usage&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Clone this repository
git clone https://github.com/tungeric/SoundCrown.git

# Go to the repository
cd soundcrown-app

# install dependencies
npm install

# initiate your server
rails server

# navigate to localhost:3000
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to upload files, you will need to make an account on Amazon Web Services and generate your security access codes to place in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config/application.yml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project uses a few open source, particularly for the music playback portion (see below). The music playbar was a heavily modified version of the React Music Player by smronju: (https://github.com/smronju/React-Music-Player) and the music animation is from Joshuasm32 (https://codepen.io/Joshuasm32/pen/IDxKB).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ss4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;ss4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took a dropdown menu from mlaursen’s react-dd-menu (https://github.com/mlaursen/react-dd-menu) to enable users to edit and delete their tracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ss8.png&quot; alt=&quot;Alt text&quot; title=&quot;ss4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course major design choices and styling were an imitation of the fine work being done at &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/&quot;&gt;SoundCloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, this page uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/thoughtbot/paperclip&quot;&gt;Paperclip&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/figaro&quot;&gt;Figaro&lt;/a&gt; to facilitate the upload of files to Amazon Web Server. I chose Amazon Web Server for its apparent security - the files uploaded cannot be tampered with by anyone other than myself&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big thanks for those sites mentioned above as well as the hundreds (thousands?) of posts on Google, Github and StackOverflow that helped move me along the way. And of course a big thank you to App Academy for showing me the skills necessary to build this application.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="SoundCloud" /><category term="fullstack" /><category term="ruby" /><category term="rails" /><category term="react" /><category term="redux" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SF MoMA and the Art of Staying in Love</title><link href="https://tungeric.github.io//sf-moma-and-the-art-of-staying-in-love/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SF MoMA and the Art of Staying in Love" /><published>2015-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2015-10-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://tungeric.github.io//sf-moma-and-the-art-of-staying-in-love</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://tungeric.github.io//sf-moma-and-the-art-of-staying-in-love/">&lt;p&gt;When I first stepped into the realm of adulthood (when I first got a real job) back in 2012 at a wonderful structural firm called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mka.com/&quot;&gt;Magnusson Klemencic Associates&lt;/a&gt; in Seattle, the first task I was assigned to design was a chimney for some rich dude’s mansion somewhere in the middle of Idaho.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know. Exciting stuff, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you gotta start somewhere, and that was the beginning of my relationship with the world of structural engineering. And I was involved in many different projects of varying degrees of such excitement as I started my career, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://now.uiowa.edu/sites/now.uiowa.edu/files/11_ui_school_of_music.jpg&quot;&gt;University of Iowa School of Music&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tendersontime.com/get-blog-image.php?id=MTg1&quot;&gt;The Dhirubhai Ambani International Convention and Exhibition Centre&lt;/a&gt; - I know, it’s a mouthful - but here’s the kicker: you have seen as much of the buildings as I have if you just clicked the links above. I’ve never seen those buildings go up in real life. I’ve never even seen a photo of that chimney that I designed when I first started work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent.fsnc1-1.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/12079681_10153084293521581_2377820966440906241_n.jpg?oh=bf0cb8b34b891e300d0126dccd479332&amp;amp;oe=5A7E908D&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your career to me is like any other relationship. In your youth, relationships are but dreams. You have a crush on that cute girl who sits across from you in your 2nd period Social Studies class (I made that up so don’t bother putting on your internet detective hats) just like you wonder how awesome it would be to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b0AGiq9j_Ak&quot;&gt;Be Like Mike&lt;/a&gt; and play in the NBA for a living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But eventually we figure out what we want to do or who we want to be with (some would argue that we all decide these things too early in our lives but that’s a discussion for another day) and we step into a relationship with - in my case, structural engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t all get to love what we do everyday we do it. Sure, some people are lucky and get to wake up everyday sure of themselves and are passionate in everything they do, but the reality is, sometimes we have doubts about who we’re with. Sometimes we’re not sure that we’re on the right path. Whether the issue is money or sanity, the grass does really seem greener on the other side every now and then.
And in those moments we need something to kick us in the rear end and keep us going. Something to remind us why we do what we do, to keep us motivated. And it’s different for everyone - sometimes what drives you is &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qjY_kJ-9HN_5IsczSgRutYk6UkI=/404x0:1683x853/730x487/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/15519255/nerlens1.0.jpg&quot;&gt;watching yourself get passed over by people you know you’re better than&lt;/a&gt; (love you Nerlens!). For some people, the faces of gratitude on the patient that they just saved from the brink of death is what keeps them going. Everyone has their own muse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My muse is SF MoMA. Well, the SF MoMA expansion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on SF MoMA starting back in 2013. I designed the gravity system for the building; that is, I designed the steel beams and columns that hold the building up, but I did not contribute to anything that might help you in the event of an earthquake (that’s called the lateral system). I won’t bore you with specifics of the building design process but anyway, during the construction of the building I was switched onto a new team and I never got to see the building up close and personal…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… until last winter, when I visited San Francisco with my family! I dragged them halfway across the city just so I could catch a glimpse of my pride and joy. My parents watched me in amusement seeing their 25-year-old son jump around excitedly like he was six and pointing giddily at a half finished skeleton of a building half hidden by the buildings surrounding it (let’s say our view from the street was limited at best). But it was more than just an incomplete museum expansion to me. I looked up at the pearly walls and I could say the three words that I’d always dreamed of saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I did that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent.fsnc1-1.fna.fbcdn.net/v/t31.0-8/p720x720/12080076_10153084297571581_6840914252985835204_o.jpg?oh=5c36c67eaa6b78eec6d39269206301d8&amp;amp;oe=5A762822&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, holy shit, &lt;em&gt;I did that&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean I’m not going to take all the credit. Hundreds of other people had their fingerprints all over the building. A lot of people probably had more of an impact on this building than I did. And hell, most people will never actually see much of my contributions - almost everything I designed is hidden behind walls and beneath the floors. But being able to see my work in real life, not on a computer screen and not on a piece of paper, validates to me why I do what I do. It makes the long hours and the complicated design challenges worth it. It makes me feel better about the path I’m on and where it will take me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes all it takes is just to see her face to remind ourselves what made us fall in love with her in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Everyone has their own muse.</summary></entry></feed>
